### Vandita Choudaha

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India +918462977539 | vanditachoudaha@gmail.com LinkedIn URL www.linkedin.com/in/vanditachoudaha

# **Professional Summary**

Successful HR Specialist with total Sixteen plus years of global experience. Thirteen plus in employee recruitment and retention, staff development, mediation, conflict resolution, benefits and compensation, HR records management, HR policies development and legal compliance. Demonstrated success negotiating win-win compromises, developing team building programs, and writing personnel manuals, corporate policies, job descriptions and management reports.

### **HR Skills**

HR Department Start-up
Employment Law
Exit Interview & Off
boarding; Mediation &
Advocacy; Recruitment &
Employee Life Cycle
HR Policies & Procedures
<b>Employee Data Management</b>
Disciplinary and Legal

Diversity and Inclusion Campus Recruitment Staff Recruitment & Retention **Employee Relations Alternative Dispute Resolution Benefits** Administration HR Program/Project Management; Employer Branding EVP;

Orientation, Employee Relations : Induction & On boarding **HRIS Technologies** Training & Development Performance Management Organizational Development & Change, Compliance and Audit POSH Compliance and IC Member

# **Professional Experience**

# Manager, Human Resources

Oct 2022- Till Date (Head of HR India region)

### dnata International Pvt. Ltd (Emirates Group), Bengaluru Karnataka, India

Policy review and drafting; Strategic Planning; Compliance and statutory responsibilities; Employee database supervision, Employee Relations and relationship management; Budgeting and Annual salary review, Talent planning and replacements, Complete employee life cycle, On-Boarding and Off boarding, Compliance -Employee Provident Fund and Gratuity, grievances resolution and problem solving, Reporting and collaboration with Global HR team for start process and global projects; process planning and implementation, training and development; Human Resources Operations and HR team management, Employer branding, Employee engagement and Analytics, Audit and validation and sign-off. Handling a budget for payroll 35cr additional to budgets related to Employee Engagement and Staff welfare.

# **Assistant Manager, Human Resources**

Dec 2019-Aug 2022

# Manipal Global Education Services, Manipal, Udupi Karnataka, India

Employee data management, Budgeting, Talent planning and replacements, Complete employee life cycle, On-Boarding and Off boarding, Compliance -Employee Provident Fund and Gratuity, National Pension Scheme, grievances, and problem solving, Reporting and process planning and implementation, Human Resources Operations, Employer branding, Employee engagement and Analytics, Administering Organization LinkedIn Page.

HR Generalist May 2017- Dec 2018

# Bankey (now Empowch), Virginia, USA

Managed the entire HR- recruitment cycle- hiring from various social media sites and from various universities for yearly cycle, guiding the startup and management of a full spectrum of HR operations, systems, and programs. Worked with senior management to create HR policies and procedures; recruit employees; create group benefits databases; and develop orientation, training, and incentive programs.

Manager HR Nov 2013- May 2014

# K3 TVS, Katni, India

Planning, executing, and managing a broad range of HR functions, including recruiting, and training employees, administering benefits, overseeing disciplinary action and managing HR records- and Co. chaired annual flex-enrolment meetings, resolved conflicts between employees and insurance carriers, coordinated health fairs to promote employee wellness and performed exit interviews.

Senior HR Executive Feb 2013- May 2013

# Airpush Inc., Bengaluru, India

Successfully led senior HR Executive- campus hiring from premium institutes like IITs and IISC, managed annual hiring planning and coordination, delivering pre placement talks, preparing and delivering presentations, follow-ups, sourcing and mapping of key talent from industry, conducting recruitment drive, induction, vendor management, employee engagement activities, grievances handling and problem solving, formulation of strategies for human development and growth by cutting the cost and increasing revenue, counselling, and compiling employee data, CTC calculation and all work related to payroll and employee insurance.

Executive HR May 2011- Aug2012

### Samho Gunyoung Construction Pvt. Ltd, M.P., India

Managed the entire recruitment Cycle, handling walk- ins, attendance and logbook management, draft labour contract and agreement, preparation of offer letter, appointment letter, monthly pay slips, coordination with head office and site office, salary report, documentation work related to Foreign Registration Office in India, Provident Funds forms, VAT, Service tax and forms, PT forms and ESI forms.

#### **Manager Finance and HR**

### SEE Media Services Pvt. Ltd, M.P. India

Ran the Finance and HR functions of the organization including PF, IT deductions and Professional Tax, internal audit, team Management and follow up, fund and stock management, BRS and, WC management, hiring cycle, conducting walk- ins and complete management of recruitment cycle,

coordination with manpower supply contractors, cross checking bills of payments, grievance handling problem solving, voucher preparation, working capital accounts and reporting.

# Executive Finance and HR SCS Pvt. Ltd. M.P. India

July 2007-Oct 2009

Nov2009- Apr2011

Oversaw the financial and HR activities of the organization. Responsibility for the accounting functions required to provide accurate and timely information on the financial status. Organized and further developed the financial processes, managed the finance team, provided coaching and training as required. Recruited the national Human Resources staff. Oversee the staff policy development, the co-ordination of training and general staff well-being.

#### **Education & Certifications**

Certificate for completion of Leadership Training 2023

Certificate for Strategic HR, LinkedIn August 2019

Certificates for Employee Engagement February 2019

Certificate for Employee experience LinkedIn, April 2019

Advanced Diploma in Human Resource, Ajax Management Consultant, Bangalore, 2012

Certified in Tally 9.2

Master of Commerce, Marketing, University RDVV, Jabalpur, 2008

 $Master\ of\ Business\ Administration\ - HR\ \&\ Finance,\ University\ RDVV,\ Jabalpur,\ 2007\ (\textbf{Gold\ Medalist})$ 

Diploma Certification in Strategic Finance and Control, ICFAI University, Hyderabad, 2007

#### **Awards & Honours**

Received Award for Business Enabling Excellence for the smooth transitioning of Employees from another acquired unit during peak pandemic and complete Lockdown time. (April 2020, for client Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Karnataka, India).

Recognized in the Social Media Team for organically increasing around 22000+ followers in LinkedIn Page through enriched contents and updates about the Organization (December, 2021, Client Base Office at Manipal, MAHE, Karnataka, India).

Sukran - Appreciation for contributing to Strategic Planning and ideas at Global level in annual Emirates HR Global Conference 2024

# **Computer Skills**

HRIS applications (OrangeHRM); HRMS

People soft -ESS; ADP-Payroll;

ESP (Employee Service Portal) and in house MSPM People software.

MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook)

Python Programming, Certifications - Coursera, Rice University, 2015.

### **Special Projects**

### The Women's Centre (Vienna, VA, USA)

Oct 2014 - Sept 2015

Worked as a technology and database management intern and graduated from career transition program for professional women. Helped across multiple projects with expertise in data management, software analysis, manual testing, planning and implementation. Also improved webbased low-cost platforms using HTML CSS coding skills and leadership ability.

#### Central Library (Arlington, VA, USA)

**Mar 2015 – June 2015** 

Worked as catalogue maintenance staff in Material Management Department for helping with labelling and database management of thousands of Books, CDs and DVDs for Arlington County' Central library. Project required meticulous planning and attention to details. Also learned library software program for billing purposes.

# Overseas Volunteer for a Better India (Washington DC, USA) Feb2015 - Jan2017

Volunteered for the International Yoga Day on 21st June 2015, Washington DC. Work involved managing and collaborating with teams across 100 different cities in the USA in collaboration with the Embassy of India in Washington DC. I was also involved in strategy development for women empowerment projects. Coordinated with teams in India for disaster management during December 2015 Chennai floods in India